<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Sam Martin</title>
    <link>https://sammart.in/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Sam Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sammart.in/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Management Camp 2016 Impressions</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/configuration-management-camp-2016-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/configuration-management-camp-2016-impressions/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of February I was lucky enough to attend Configuration Management Camp for the 3rd year running. The first year I attended (2013) it was my first introduction to the concept of configuration management, and god damn it was overwhelming. So many new concepts, new tools, new ideas, I left having been enlightened to a whole new world of automation.
This year, having massively improved my knowledge of modern tools and practices around automation and infrastructure, and now having worked with Chef for a couple of years, I came to cfgmgmtcamp with the goal of learning more about Docker in production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Chef on Windows Server - Part 3a - Packer, Vagrant, and Vagrant Omnibus</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3a-packer-vagrant-and-vagrant-omnibus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3a-packer-vagrant-and-vagrant-omnibus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction – HashiCorp Atlas It’s been a fair few months since my last post in this series (or at all for this matter) and I haven’t made anywhere near the progress with Chefifying (definitely a word) my environment as I would like due to new more urgent projects.
Since my last post, HashiCorp has announced Atlas as a tech preview, which (in part) replaces VagrantCloud which I referenced in part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeanKit integration with ticketing system (using PowerShell)</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/leankit-integration-with-ticketing-system-using-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/leankit-integration-with-ticketing-system-using-powershell/</guid>
      <description>I’m no expert on Kanban by any means, but ever since reading The Phoenix Project, I’ve been dying to try it out in the workplace.
For me, there are four key things that I think Kanban can help us do that our current tools can’t:
 Identify queue time &amp;amp; bottlenecks Visualise Work In Process (WIP) Prioritise work (Queued or In Process) Promote mono-tasking by enforcing WIP limits  History However, we’ve recently come out the far side of a meta-project to improve the visibility and predicitability of project work by introducing a tool called Clarizen, which has resulted in the tool being scrapped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>