<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Sam Martin</title>
    <link>https://sammart.in/categories/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Sam Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sammart.in/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Kitchen with a SQL Server Dependency</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/test-kitchen-with-a-sql-server-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/test-kitchen-with-a-sql-server-dependency/</guid>
      <description>I want to be able to test my cookbooks/scripts without having to rely on independent testing infrastructure! I want to be able to do kitchen converge and have all my infrastructure ready to go without any further thought to the dependencies!
This is why I’m such a huge fan of Matt Wrock’s Kitchen-Nodes. It’s a provisioner wrapper around Chef-Zero for Test Kitchen, which allows you to access some of the attributes from other nodes which you’re provisioning in Test Kitchen using Chef Search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Chef on Windows Server - Part 3a - Packer, Vagrant, and Vagrant Omnibus</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3a-packer-vagrant-and-vagrant-omnibus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3a-packer-vagrant-and-vagrant-omnibus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction – HashiCorp Atlas It’s been a fair few months since my last post in this series (or at all for this matter) and I haven’t made anywhere near the progress with Chefifying (definitely a word) my environment as I would like due to new more urgent projects.
Since my last post, HashiCorp has announced Atlas as a tech preview, which (in part) replaces VagrantCloud which I referenced in part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Chef on Windows Server - Part 1 Intro</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server/</guid>
      <description>I’ve never had the opportunity to work with configuration management software, but a recent project has pushed me over the edge from “Wow, that sounds really cool in theory!” to “Well, I’d better get my feet wet!”.
As the learnchef.com’s Windows page is currently under construction, I thought I’d write my efforts up to help anyone who might also be getting their feet wet for the first time in the configuration management space using Chef on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Chef on Windows Server – Part 3 – Vagrant, Windows, and Managed Chef</title>
      <link>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3-vagrant-windows-and-managed-chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammart.in/post/getting-started-with-chef-on-windows-server-part-3-vagrant-windows-and-managed-chef/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two parts (Intro and Chef Server &amp;amp; Bootstrapping) we used a plain old VirtualBox VM with Windows 2012 R2 as our Chef client, which required downloading VHDs, registering them as individual VMs and then installing Chef manually. Part 2 even required that you still had your old VM from the first session lying around in order to start where you left off!
This is not very chicken farm of us, and, I’ve since learned, really doing it the hard and old-fashioned way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>